Highlander Folk School Publications 5717
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Highlander Folk School Publications
1945-1954
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Highlander Folk School
5717
0.33 cubic feet
0.3 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications (documents).
5698409
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, April 06, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 28, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5898 mf: FBI Files on Highlander Folk School on Microfilm
Highlander Folk School
5698409
- Correspondence and Press Releases, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Education Unlimited, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By Mary Lawrance. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: 21st Annual Report, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Highlander Folk School. October 1, 1952 - September 30, 1953. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Proposed Follow-Up on the Supreme Court Decisions and the Public Schools Workshop, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Myles Horton. Includes letter from Myles Horton to Kermit Eby, dated 24Nov53. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Special Report to the Highlander Executive Council Members, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Myles Horton. November 11, 1953. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Highlander Folk School 20th Annual Report, 1932-1952, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Highlander Folk School. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: The Supreme Court Decisions and the Public Schools Workshop, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Myles Horton. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Statement by Myles Horton in connection with hearins before subcommittee on Internal Security., Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Myles Horton. New Orleans, March 18-24, 1954. Includes circular cover letter to "Dear Friend of Highlander" by Myles Horton, dated April 3, 1954. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Statement of Myles Horton in Connection with Hearings Before Subcommittee on Internal Security of the Senate Judiciary Committee, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Myles Horton. New Orleans, March 18, 1954. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: News from Highlander, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Myles Horton; Zilphia Horton; Henry Shipherd; Betty Shipherd. September, 1954. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: A Letter which was not printed, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Hans J. Morgenthau. Letter to the editor of the New York Times, dated November 9, 1954. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Press Release, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Highlander Folk School. July 20, 1953. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Proposed Follow-Up on the Supreme Court Decisions and the Public Schools Workshop, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Highlander Folk School. August - September, 1953. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Press Release, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Highlander Folk School. September 22, 1953. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Integration of the Public Schools: Check List, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Highlander Folk School. July 12 - August 8, 1953. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Teachers and Integration: Workshop, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Highlander Folk School. August 9, 1953. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: Excerpt from letter from Nancy Gough [to Myles Horton], Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Nancy Gough. July 12, 1954. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Summary of Discussions on Goals and Procedures for Community Action on the Supreme Court Decision on Segregation in the Public Schools Workshop, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Highlander Folk School. June 27 - July 4, 1954. Item is in English.
- Reports and Correspondence, 1948-1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: To All the members of the Chicago Committee for Highlander Folk School, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By John B. Thompson. Circular letter dated February 19, 1952. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: 18th Annual Report, 1932-1950, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Executive Council Meeting Minutes., Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Highlander Folk School. November 29-30, 1950. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Statement of Purpose, Program, and Policy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Highlander Folk School. April 3, 1950. Includes correspondence. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: 19th Annual Report, 1932-1951, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Financial Report, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Highlander Folk School. October 1, 1950 - September 30, 1951. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Horton Named New Education Director, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Myles Horton. Memo and news clipping from The Packinghouse Worker, v.10:no.10 (1951:Oct.). Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Memo from Highlander Folk School, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: September Memo, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Joanna Willimetz. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Highlander Reports, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 11: Help Win Democracy in the South and Win for All America, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Freedom's Call. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Correspondence. Letter to Mrs. Louis S. Weiss from Mrs. Emil Willimetz, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 13: Report on the Highlander Dinner, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Bea Schneiderman. February 22, 1952. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: The Highlander Fling, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Highlander Folk School. v.6:no.5 (1948:June). Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Highlander Folk School, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Article. December, 1949. pp.12-14. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: The Program at Highlander, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Myles Horton. Article. December, 1949. pp.14-16. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Greetings from Highlander, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Myles Horton. Circular letter. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: 19th Annual Report, 1932-1951, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Highlander Folk School. second copy. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: Partial Education Department Report, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Myles Horton. March 20, 1952. Item is in English.
  - Item 20: Highlander's Story, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By R. A. Behymer. Item is in English.
  - Item 21: Program Highlights, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Highlander Folk School. October 1951 - March 1952. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: The Nursery School children have been delighted with the advent of barefoot, "crawdad" fishing weather., Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Labor's Scrapbook, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Poems, songs, and short prose.
  - Item 1: Labor's Scrapbook, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Poems, songs, and short prose. Item is in English.